<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<prompt xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="https://jabrena.github.io/pml/schemas/0.3.0/pml.xsd">

    <title>Solve a AOC puzzle using TDD</title>

    <role>You are a Senior software engineer with extensive experience in Java software development</role>

    <goal>
        Solve a AOC puzzle using TDD.
        Follow the next steps to achieve the goal.
    </goal>

    <steps>
        <step number="1">
            <step-title>Understand the whole project</step-title>
            <step-content>
                Review the whole repository to understand the different maven modules and the purpose of each module.

                Put focus in the module `commons` to understand how to desing the classes
                Put focus in the module third-party/aoc just in case you could use one of the classes to model your solutions
                Review the modules with a numerical name to understand problems solved in the past years.
            </step-content>
        </step>
        <step number="2">
            <step-title>Identify what problem to solve</step-title>
            <step-content>
                Execute the command:

                ```bash
                jbang aoc@jabrena pending
                ```

                to return what years has pending problem to solve.

                It will return a list of years like: `2015 2016 2017 2018 2019 2020 2021 2022 2023
                2024 2025`

                Use 2018 as YEAR.

                and pass that YEAR to the following command:

                ```bash
                jbang aoc@jabrena pending YEAR
                ```

                that command will return a list of strings representing the days and parts pending
                to be solved.

                Example: `1_1 2_1 3_1 4_1 5_1 6_1 7_1 8_1 9_1 10_1 11_1 12_1 13_1 14_1 15_1 16_1
                17_1 18_1 19_1 20_1 21_1 22_1 23_1 24_1 25_1`

                From that result, get the FIRST value from the list which has the following schema:

                ```bash
                Example: `1_1` which it means DAY=1 (First part in the string) and PART=1 (Second
                part in the string);

                DAY contains values from 1-25 and PART could have values 1 or 2 and in this case,
                PART=1

                Know you have that you are going to resolve a problem for YEAR, DAY and PART.
            </step-content>
        </step>
        <step number="3">
            <step-title>Create input data</step-title>
            <step-content>
                In the maven module YEAR identified in the previous step,

                review if exist in path `src/test/resources` the folder named `dayX`, where X is the value of DAY
                in other case, create in the path: `src/test/resources` create a folder named `dayX` where X is the value of DAY.

                inside of that folder review if exist the file `dayX-input.txt`, where X is the value of DAY
                in other case, create a file named `dayX-input.txt` and put the content from the output of the command:

                ```bash
                jbang aoc@jabrena input YEAR DAY
                ```
            </step-content>
        </step>
        <step number="4">
            <step-title>Create a Unit Test (Red phase of TDD for part 1 or part 2)</step-title>
            <step-content>
                In the maven module YEAR, review if exist in path `src/test/java/info/jab/aoc` a previous package
                for dayX where X is the value of DAY in other case, create the unit test.
                Create a new package in the path `YEAR/src/test/java/info/jab/aoc` named `dayX` where X is the value of DAY.

                In order to desing a goog Unit Test, you need to undertand the problem with the command:

                ```bash
                jbang aoc@jabrena problem YEAR X
                ```

                review the problem statement and once you understand the problem,

                create the Unit Test in the package `dayX`, where X is the value of DAY, with the name `DayXTest.java`
                and add a Java Unit Test for First part only.

                In the Test implementation if you need to define a future Java class which will be implemented in the next step,
                take this example:

<![CDATA[
```java
package info.jab.aoc.dayX;

import info.jab.aoc.Solver;

public class DayX implements Solver<Integer> {

    @Override
    public Integer solvePartOne(String fileName) {
        throw new UnsupportedOperationException("Not implemented");
    }

    @Override
    public Integer solvePartTwo(String fileName) {
        throw new UnsupportedOperationException("Not implemented");
    }
}
```
]]>

                Note: Review if exist the class `DayX.java` in the path
                `YEAR/src/main/java/info/jab/aoc/dayX/DayX.java`
                in other case, create it with the name `DayX.java` where X is the value of DAY.
                Note: Not create any solution, just the class implementing the interface <![CDATA[ `Solver<T>` ]]> throwing an
                UnsupportedOperationException if the class didn´t exist before.

                In this phase following TDD, the test will pass the file name representing the input
                data to the future Java solution.

                Review examples in the path `YEAR/src/test/java/info/jab/aoc/dayX/DayXTest.java`,
                where X is the value of DAY.

                If you execute the tests with:

                ```bash
                ./mvnw clean test -pl YEAR -am
                ```

                Note: Replace YEAR with the value of the year that you are working on and DAY with
                the value of the day that you are working on.

                It will fail, but it is fine, it is part of the TDD process to achieve the Green
                phase.

                Note: Remember to add Timeout (30 seconds) limits for Junit test to avoid a infinite
                waiting behaviour.

                Print in the console that you are in the Red phase of TDD.

                Commit and push the initial test and the java class empty to the repository.
            </step-content>
        </step>
        <step number="5">
            <step-title>Create a Java class with the solution (Green phase of TDD for part 1 or part 2)</step-title>
            <step-content>
                In the maven module YEAR, in the package `info.jab.aoc`,

                review if exist a class `DayX.java` in the path
                `YEAR/src/main/java/info/jab/aoc/dayX/DayX.java` where X is the value of DAY
                in other case, create the new java class with the name `DayX.java` in the path
                `YEAR/src/main/java/info/jab/aoc/dayX/DayX.java` where X is the value of DAY.

                In this Java class implement the solution to resolve the problem returned from the
                command:

                ```bash
                jbang aoc@jabrena problem YEAR DAY
                ```

                using the imput from:

                ```bash
                jbang aoc@jabrena input YEAR DAY
                ```

                Note: change the value DAY with the day that you processed previously.

                With the problem statement and the input, develop the solution in the Java class.
                Note: Only resolve the solution for the part 1 or part 2 that you are working on
                depending of the value of PART.

                print the solution in the test and extract from that maven test execution the RESULT
                of the part 1 or part 2.

                use that RESULT to verify if the problem was resolved with the following command:
                ```bash
                jbang aoc@jabrena submit YEAR DAY PART RESULT
                ```

                Note: Replace YEAR with the value of the year that you are working on
                and DAY with the value of the day that you are working on
                and PART with the value of the part that you are working on (1 or 2).

                if the command returns: "Wrong answer", you need to iterate the solution because it
                was not resolved.
                if the command returns: "Correct answer", you need to update the unit test with the
                right assert asserting the result.
                if the command returns: "Rate limited", you need to wait 1 minute and try again
                before submit the answer.
                if the command returns: "Unexpected response", you need to update the unit test with
                the right assert asserting the result.

                Verify that everything works with

                ```bash
                ./mvnw clean verify
                ```

                Print in the console that you are in the Green phase of TDD.

                Commit the Java Class with the solution to the repository
                and the Unit Test to the repository if it was updated.

                If everything goes well, you achieved the goal.
            </step-content>
            <step-constraints>
                <step-constraint-list>
                    <step-constraint>Verify that test load the input file</step-constraint>
                    <step-constraint>Verify that java solution take the input from the test</step-constraint>
                    <step-constraint>Verify that test has the right assert asserting the result</step-constraint>
                    <step-constraint>Verify that the java solution doesn't have any main method</step-constraint>
                    <step-constraint>Verify that the input file has the right format: `dayX-input.txt`</step-constraint>
                    <step-constraint>Verify that tests has timeout of 30 seconds</step-constraint>
                </step-constraint-list>
            </step-constraints>
        </step>
        <step number="6">
            <step-title>Solve the problem for part 2</step-title>
            <step-content>
                Repeat the steps 4 and 5 for part 2.
            </step-content>
        </step>

    </steps>

    <safeguards>
        <safeguards-list>
            <safeguards-item>Verify that in the maven module YEAR is successfully built with `./mvnw clean verify` and the tests pass</safeguards-item>
            <safeguards-item>Verify that the problem is solved for part 1 with the verification of the command `jbang aoc@jabrena submit YEAR DAY PART RESULT`</safeguards-item>
            <safeguards-item>Verify that the problem is solved for part 2 with the verification of the command `jbang aoc@jabrena submit YEAR DAY PART RESULT`</safeguards-item>
        </safeguards-list>
    </safeguards>

    <acceptance-criteria>
        <acceptance-criteria-list>
            <acceptance-criteria-item>The problem is solved with the verification of the command `jbang aoc@jabrena submit YEAR DAY PART RESULT` for part 1 and part 2</acceptance-criteria-item>
            <acceptance-criteria-item>The unit test is successful with the verification of the command `./mvnw clean test -pl YEAR -am`</acceptance-criteria-item>
        </acceptance-criteria-list>
    </acceptance-criteria>
</prompt>
